When I first started, I was at Agora
Financial. I had one promotion make $15
million. Someone came and poached me
from Agora, asked me to come work at
WealthPress and show them like the Agora
way. They were doing 2 million when I
got there. The next year we did $50
million in sales. I'll tell you what Joe
taught us at Agora was the daily
practice is read a piece of copy, write
a piece of copy, come up with an idea
every day. I've been doing it for like a
decade every day.
>> So, with that said, there's a reason we
have these laptops here. We're actually
going to do something special today.
We're going to be reviewing a little bit
of copy live. So, uh, let's get into it.
>> All right, cool. So, this one is about
the million or more saved. So, there is
something new sort of. As soon as he
said some wealthy people earn returns,
you start to lose me. 18 percentage
points higher on the same types of
investments. We got what I call double
mumbo jumbo. All right, that means
you've introduced two veiled concepts
that I don't fully understand in one
line. There's too much happening right
there and none of it's concrete. This is
for Vshred. Can you guess which of these
everyday foods could help your body burn
fat faster? So, he's following the
formula pattern interrupt question. And
then he's got a trigger BS, but none of
them are especially strong. You could
have done more. We've talked about
texture a lot today. Every one of these
lines is an opportunity to add what you
call texture or technique. How would I
know what technique? Read the copy.
Copywriters. I think they get in their
own way. They start skipping steps and
they fill in the blanks with their
brain. Stop thinking cuz you're stupid.
Like we have rules, we have swipes, we
have proven formulas, frameworks, and we
have proven promotions that made
millions. If you would just like spend 2
hours bulleting out your swipe, you can
write the whole thing in like an hour.
>> I love it. This has been fantastic. It's
been a master class on breaking down
copy, researching, getting out of your
own way, and then writing a lot of stuff
and making a bazillion dollars.
Today, literally, I was reviewing some
copy and
it's like just no context. Here's an
email. I'm like, cool. Where's your
research?
What's the what's your unique selling
point? And and I asked the copyright, I
said, "Hey, so what's um is this the
best lead you can write?" And they're
like, "No."
I'm like, "So, so then I'm writing
>> I'm writing your lead then, right?" So,
it's called I this is what I call it,
Big Daddy Kyle. And so, I have like the
individuals I've worked with. I've got
writers that I pay to write promos for
my agency. And then I've got like
consulting clients and I talk to them
all about this. It's like, do not do
this. So, Big Daddy Kyle is when I will
give enough of an effort that it looks
like copy and then
Big Daddy Kyle will come in and fix all
the errors, make it good and I'll be a
hero.
>> Yeah. And so one of the ways that I've
had to separate myself from that problem
because no matter how many times you say
it, like that's the thing, like there
are certain things that no matter how
many times you yell and threaten and
shame, like I use shame like a weapon,
dude, when we have like the team calls,
I'm like, "What the [__] is this?"
>> Like
you, what do we do in the first four
lines? You, what are we doing in the
first four lines? You, what are we doing
in the first four lines? What the [__]
is this? like everyone knows, but you
know, you made the bozo mistake. I'll
I'll shame people in a heartbeat. It's
good for them. But so you can yell at
them, threaten them, shame them, and
there are some things that they will
just it's just never going to end. So
for me, I have started
I have actually for the first time ever
pulled myself away from royalties. It's
the first time I've ever done something
without royalties attached. And it's the
consulting stuff. And I tell the
publisher, I say, I will coach your
writers,
>> I'm not writing their copy. Like, the
problem is so bad and so prevalent and
never like incessant.
>> Yeah, it's annoying.
>> Uh that I even make it clear to the
publisher, like I'll get on a weekly
call with your team and go through their
copy with them. I'll give them feedback.
I'll tell them what's wrong and what I
would do,
>> but my finger touches a keyboard,
they're off, and I get royalties. Yeah,
>> because as soon as you insert them, my
workload somehow like magically doubles
into like this isn't going to work. I
got to rewrite
>> is an understatement of what happens.
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz you write a single piece and then
it's now the whole promotion's basically
like no you it has your blessing behind
it, you know? Meanwhile meanwhile it's
like you edited the first two lines and
they didn't take the feedback and put it
through the rest of the whatever.
>> There's a mistake. I mean like so when
I'm at a when I first started I was at
Agora Financial the 800 pound gorilla it
was in its heyday it was like the
biggest thing in financial publishing
and direct response in general and I
learned a lot of things like you know
it's a volume game you know like one out
of every six promos one out of every
eight promos works and if you're good
it's more like one out of every five or
one out of every four if you're good
like if you're great. And so when I
started my agency and I had writers
under me, it was like I want them to
learn and I want but then who ends up
taking the lumps like I'm like let's go
ahead and try this even though it's not
like basically to our standards
necessarily follow all of our rules. Let
them learn. You know, I had a I've had
I've had projects go out that made
literally zero sales. And because my
name's attached because I'm it's my
agency and I'm the copy chief. And it's
like, and the other thing about that is
in financial publishing, you're telling
a story. So, it's like if the story
doesn't resonate on like half page one,
like the first, that's why I say the
first four lines. I know in six lines if
this is like a complete bomb, like if
it's going to confuse the [__] out of
the reader, all this stuff. And uh it's
possible to write a promo in financial
publishing and get crickets
>> because if someone checks out, if most
people check out like after the first
like couple minutes, no one's obviously
going to make it to the one hour mark of
like because all we're doing is like
long form VSSL style storytelling and
stuff like that. And uh yeah, man, it's
been, you know, it's probably not the
coolest way to start a podcast is be
like, "Yeah, I've had maybe it's a good
thing to say. I've had massive bombs
like uh that have happened and they were
attached to my agency and I had to take
the lumps on that,
>> but it was in the spirit of trying to
like let people sort of make mistakes on
their own, try things their way, and let
them cuz it's like some people got to
touch the hot stove."
But yeah, like I was just saying, I'm
sort of like stepping back on that a
little bit because it's like, you know,
you don't get a million second chances.
You don't get a like you you throw you
don't get the grace of being an in-house
writer if you're an agency.
>> You get like I paid you to do this and
do it well
>> and it didn't work.
>> You know, aren't you supposed to be the
big shot?
>> And you can't really be like, "Yeah, but
you know, one in five promos works."
like you never
>> like [laughter]
all right we'll write four more you know
like so the all of this encapsulates
like all of this trauma I have around
big daddy Kyle
>> which is exactly like what you're
describing where they just drop it at
your lap like they know it's not their
best work but that's why they got you
>> that's right
>> you'll do it all for them
>> well I've been saying that you know if
you want me to start writing I'm going
to start charging using my copyrights,
you know. So, I'm glad we've kind of
reached the same same conclusion on this
because it is really um it is really
lazy and it's got worse ever since AI
cuz before AI, I was writing stuff. I
was doing okay, you know, and now with
AI, I didn't use it for like the first
few years cuz I was like, it's the
amount of time it takes me to prompt AI
and what I want. I just write it myself,
honestly. Like, I'll just write it
myself. But um newer copyriters, they
don't have that skill yet. So it's very
tempting to be like, "Hey, let me just
write everything with AI, ask AI to do
it for me." It's like, "Hey, like not
even joking. I had a copyrighter I was
coaching who um he took feedback from
the call. He took his Fathom or his
notetaker, whatever. He took all my
feedback from the call and he shared it
with Claude and he's like, "Here's my
copy. Here's Matt's feedback." like make
the changes
to the copy.
>> And how did that go?
>> It was way worse.
>> Really?
>> Yeah, it was worse.
>> Even with the the direction of the
feedback, the AI still couldn't like
>> Well, yeah, because because it wasn't
because I gave feedback on the general
idea. I said what it should be, what it
shouldn't be, you know, like the
delivery, what's wrong about the copy. I
didn't want to like it's like control
altdelete. I mean, control a delete.
Like this is not copy that you can it
can survive.
>> So like more editing of the copy. I
think this is another thing that
copyriters need to pay attention to when
it comes to like how you edit copy.
There's like three or four um levels of
editing depending on your school of
training. You know, you've got like your
idea editing, you've got your like flow
editing or your functional editing and
then you got like the actual line by
line and proof proof copy editing. And I
think that most copywriters when they
get critique, they're like waiting for
the word, especially newer copyriters,
they're waiting for like that wordby
word critique. when it's like I don't
even want to go into the word by word
because the entire theme of this whole
message you lost me on sentence too like
what's the point of sitting there trying
to fix something that's you know
>> I like what you said about the different
levels of editing so what I would do I
have and that's another thing is like
everybody you read any of these copy
books after doing it for a few years you
realize like oh we've all sort of
reached the same conclusion with
different labels but for me it would be
like the unique promise is the idea
level and I've got two formulas. If it's
mechanism driven, the formula is my
mechanism exploits force of nature to
deliver a result.
>> Force of nature.
>> It's a force of nature. It's an
opportunity, an anomaly phenomenon.
Yeah.
>> But the mechanism has to be exploiting
something. So like a level one
copywriter just go straight. My
mechanism is the best.
>> It's the best mechanism. Get this
mechanism. M
>> an actual like a like if you have so if
you have like a system that repeatedly
delivers a uniform result you need a
force of nature because the force of
nature is where the story is. You could
do a mechanism story about the discovery
and the origins and the blood sweat
tears and building the mechanism and
that's sort of like a hero's journey
sort of discovery story kind of thing.
But the real story that people care
about that would give them the aha is
discovering there's a force of nature at
play. And the force of nature is what
makes this it's it's the process. It's
the thing that's cyclical and timeless
that'll always be there. It's just like
part and parcel with the situation at
hand. It's arbitration. It's momentum.
It's it's whatever the hell that you're
exploiting.
>> And so you can tell a story around that.
So it's like this is something that I I
just came to my mind. Um, are you into
meditation at all?
>> Not really. No.
>> I'll explain a little bit about like I
don't know if this is gonna play or not,
but
there's basically mind and emotion.
There's thoughts and emotion. A lot of
times when you're having a feeling, your
mind will have a narrative to justify
that feeling. I'm angry because
the idea of like meditation and like
letting go of emotion, feeling your
feelings, all that stuff. Release all
that is the idea of like just
experiencing the emotion and
knowing that the narrative is probably
false.
>> All right.
So with the force of nature, it is sort
of like there. It's dormant. It just is.
With copy, what you can do is you can
attribute a narrative to that force of
nature. So, one of my biggest successes
ever was about unusual options activity.
So, the thing is in financial
publishing, there's only like four or
five things you can really, it's always
buy low, sell high. In health, it's it's
it's um well, if it's weight loss
health, it would be consume fewer
calories than you burn,
>> right? How are we going to spin that
into a new supplement, a new diet, a new
training regimen? It's the force of
nature. It's always the same.
>> So with mine, it was unusual options
activity was like the mechanism and it's
exploiting this information advantage
that insiders have. Insiders always have
information first,
>> right? They're there when it happens.
So
I created this I I didn't really create
the narrative. I researched it. Yeah.
>> Which we can dive into research.
>> And I found basically this one
journalist like beating the drum about
insider trading. Like I read like three
of her articles I think and it gave me
like everything I needed to show the
picture of like look Enron was evil and
they they built all their investors out
of bajillions of dollars lost millions
of jobs and everyone went broke and
homeless that caused Sarbain Oxley which
was like this thing to create more
strict auditing standards for
accounting.
This caused a bigger gap between the
information availability and the time
from it happening to like has to go
through all the auditing procedures to
it getting to the public.
And now
the public gets their information 14
days on average behind the actual
events.
And so that is a force of nature, the
idea that insiders have information. But
notice how I just gave it a whole
because a whole narrative, a whole
origin. I could tell a million stories.
You could talk about Nancy Pelosi.
>> Nancy Pelosi somehow never fails at
trading stocks. She's a congressperson.
She makes laws. And you could I mean
there's a million different stories I
could spin about this one force of
nature.
>> And so that's kind of probably
well that is definitely I've got like
two two or three things as like a guru.
The big one, the first one I ever
thought of was Nesby, new, easy, safe,
and big. Those are like the four core
emotions. So when you talk about like
levels, I got my unique promise, which
would be mechanism, force of nature,
result for a mechanism driven promo. And
then for an opportunity driven promo,
like something just [__] happened.
You got to get rich. I'm going to show
you how to get rich off this thing that
just happened. If it's an opportunity
promo, the formula becomes there's a
catalyst that just happened.
And then there's an implied
force of nature.
>> Okay?
>> Which means this catalyst is a
repetition of some timeless event
pattern. You don't necessarily call the
force of nature out, but it's part of
your research because you have to say
it's happening again just like last time
when it happened with this and that.
That's the force of nature. It's the
revolutions. It's another revolution.
>> Catalyst is triggering another force in
nature that always delivers this result.
and I have the blueprint, plan,
strategy, mechanism to take advantage of
this thing. So that's an opportunity
promo for a unique promise. So the next
level would be the beats. That's what I
call the beats of a sales letter. I got
this from Save the Cat by Blake
Schneider, which is like a
screenwriting. I bet your boy loves that
book. You know that book, Save the Cat,
Blake Schneider? It's a Hollywood
screenplay book. It was basically the
first time someone like laid out how all
movies are the same or it was like that
was very I guess publicly consumed. So I
I took that idea of like a three-act
structure, the beats of a Hollywood
screenplay and I sort of laid out the
beats of a sales letter which would be
the flow and the structure and the
argumentation.
Below that would be techniques for each
section. So a problem section you got
like three ways you can write a problem
section. Three ways you can introduce
catalyst all that sorts of stuff. And
then at the atomic level, what are the
power words? How do I stoke emotion?
At the atomic like proton like like
think of it like proteins like the
building blocks of copy would be new,
easy, safe, and big that if I'm going to
talk about literally anything, it needs
to come through the frame that this is a
new gamechanging earthshattering
situation that anybody can take
advantage of. Even if you're armless,
legless, and blind. And it's the safest,
most credible, repeatable, obvious
solution ever. And it's going to happen
in the next 4 seconds for you if you do
it my way.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. So, whatever whatever research
you're presenting has to come through
one of those
>> limbs. Yeah.
>> You had a you had a you had a giggle,
man. Like a knowing giggle. What was
that?
>> I freaking love copy. It's funny. It's
funny to come up with this stuff, you
know, because it's like I think some
copywriters, they they create the
mechanism out of thin air to do the
selling, but the way I've seen it done
best is you kind of discover that from
within what's happening and then you
build the narrative like you've said
around it, right? Because that way when
they do their research, when the
consumer does the research, it confirms
your idea and sort of sells them away.
Like I've seen many info coaches, they
just create a mechanism out of thin air
because they look at the surface of
marketing and they don't understand
what's happening and they're like oh you
know my system for this that and the
other and you do any research there's
nothing there. it's not founded upon
anything and then it's like it actually
works against you then you know so so I
just I just love um being able to take
yeah I love taking ideas and making them
fun easy simple new fresh feel like this
is the biggest thing that's happened
since uh you know I don't know Bitcoin
or do bubble or something you know
>> one of those guys I don't know the the
old like 60s30s whenever early days
copywriting gurus
Was it Capable or Schwarz or something
like that said great copy is assembled
>> not written or something like that.
>> I've heard this one. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean again like everybody
eventually gets there. Like so for
instance if you want to say um it's you
know my solution is the fastest. That
sucks. It's technically correct because
it's say it's it's the fast emotion. So
it's new, easy, safe and big all have
alter egos that amplify them. So new is
only. So it's new. But to to make that
really feel very real and palatable is
like I invented it. It's only available
through me. It's my proprietary super
secret system
>> only. Yeah.
>> Easy. And then anybody. So it's like
yeah, it's easy. It's three steps. It's
just a push button solution. It's blah
blah blah. So the onelegged golfer ad is
like a one-legged golfer could do this.
Anybody could do this. And then there's
safe uh safe is credibility, but
predictability. So safe and predictable.
Predictable means like I show you over
and over and over and over and over it
worked.
>> Yeah.
>> Safe would be more like a NASA scientist
engineered this and so we know it's
credible and we can trust it.
>> And then the last one is big and it's
alter ego would be like yeah you're
going to make a million dollars
tomorrow. So big's alter ego is fast. So
when I say like the fast emotion but
yeah um you could say your thing is the
fastest thing which again technically
you did it right. Right. But it sucks.
Um, and what I'll see is like like you
know keyword stuffing for like YouTube
and SEO, they do it with NSBY. They do
like people who learn about Nesby, they
do NESBY stuffing. There's a
gamechanging breakthrough solution
that's so easy and has worked for
decades and it's going to make you it's
going to change your life now. Like it
like becomes n and then every line is
like that.
Whereas you could have said, "Look, um,
AI is going to make you richer than
anything we've ever seen before at a
pace never before seen in history." I
for example, it took seven years for
cell phones to be to hit a million
users. It took 15 years for the internet
to hit a million users, but did you know
it took chat GPT seven days to hit a
million users? So, you could do
something like I'm demonstrating that
it's
>> really good. Yeah, it's really
interesting. So that way you can keep it
fresh instead of having the same
>> but that's the research.
>> That's the difference between
>> making [__] up, which is the colloquial
way that I call what you said, like
making a mechanism out of thin air.
>> Making [__] up. Yeah.
>> What you'll see in my if you if you work
for me or I'm doing your copy, like
critiquing it, a comment from me will
say you wrote this. And if if you know
me and you've been working with me, you
know what that means? It means bad. It
means you came up with this [__] in
your stupid brain and like it's
>> it's amazing.
>> Yeah, it that's exactly what that means.
And you should feel the sting of the
shame like I I caught you. I caught you
trying to slip one by me. I can tell you
broke away from the research and you
started getting fancy.
>> And so our philosophy at the copy squad
is do the least. And the idea here is I
want to
>> That's easy.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I want to absolutely like
the biggest problem with copywriting
that the hurdle that they run into is
spinning the wheels. And the spinning of
the wheels comes from this weird dance
they do where they create their own
problems and then they try to solve
them. And they think their way into this
problem. And it's like stop thinking
like we have rules, we have swipes, we
have proven formulas, frameworks, and we
have proven promotions that made
millions.
Why the [__] And this is where the this
is a concept that I call four punches.
So like if you learn to fight, you'll
learn like the jab, the cross, the hook,
the uppercut. You'll know your basic
punches. You in your third week of
training don't think you're not bold
enough to imagine that you're going to
come up with the new [__] punch,
right? You're not gonna go in there and
be like, I'll show I'll show my sensei
like some [__] he ain't never seen
before.
>> And then every time a [__] new
copywriter sits down and they start
writing without a swipe or a template or
a framework, they're inventing a new
[__] punch.
>> And it looks like this [__] right here.
Looks like like what the [__] are you
doing?
>> Like I'm I'm reading this like what is
this? I have never I've read hundreds
maybe thousands of promos now. I have
never seen a section like this.
[laughter]
Where did you get this?
>> Did you get it from your swipe? Did you
get it from any of the research? Like
what is this? Sounded cool. It's just
horseshit.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> Yeah. So that's like my daily life.
>> I get it. I get it. It's It's a really
It's an ego thing. Do you think it's
ego?
>> I think. Uhuh. Uhuh. I think it's
laziness.
>> It's lazy. I don't think they are like
No, because they'll fold in a minute
like as soon as you call them on it.
Yeah. Like
[laughter]
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, it's true.
You asked like, "What is this? Where's
your research for this?" So, I asked
somebody the other day. We should make
the title of this video like like
Matthew and Carl like [__] talking
copyrighters or something.
>> Dude, I can [__] I've got so many
experiences
like working with copywriters and here's
the other thing. They're not bad people.
That's the other thing. Do I think
they're ego? No. I think a lot of them
are really hardworking. I think they get
in their own way. They That's where do
the lease comes in. And you wrote this.
Why did you write this? Like why did you
when I when I So we have a process
called 531.
Very straightforward. Read five relevant
promos with a similar offer and
mechanism.
Bullet out the claims and proof like the
sales argumentation for three of them.
So you've read all five. Now you're
going back and you're bulleting three of
them. At this point that [__] should
start to get burned in your brain how to
present this.
>> Then you're going to marry one. This is
going to be your boo thing. Like this is
the one that you're going to look to
every time you start to get a little bit
stuck.
>> Stop thinking cuz you're [__] stupid.
Like your brain knows nothing, man.
Like, [laughter]
>> oh [__]
>> You have you've got to like let the
process do its thing and trust in the
swipe and trust in the frameworks
>> and like and that's the thing like just
you can't
Bill Bonner I believe he's given this
quote which is like we're not in the why
business we're in the what business.
That's what they told me at Agora and
you know he's the founder of the Agora
companies, billiond dollarar company and
all that and a brilliant writer and what
he means from my understanding again is
we don't often know why something works.
We just know that it worked, right? So I
see people like getting on Facebook
groups and like what do you think about
this advertisement? And it's like who
gives a [__] what you think? Like that's
my always my first thought is like did
it make a million bucks? like then then
that's the end of the discussion.
So it's like often times
you have to sort of that's where the
thinking mind comes in. You're sitting
there trying to attribute meaning and
you're sitting there trying to
understand and it's like dude it was
just like you know you slap President
Trump's name on there and you said it
was all Democrats fault and 49% of the
country said I'm going to buy that. Like
that's kind of like the the long and
short of it. Maybe it's just simple as
that.
>> So I mean the the whole concept of again
I don't think that they're egoic. I
think there's like two or three things
happening. They're well-meaning.
They get frazzled. They get in a rush
and they skip steps.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. They they default. Like so for
instance I'm working with some people
right now and they'll come to our calls.
So, this is like one of those consulting
things and I'm like,
"What the [__] is this shit?" You know,
like one of those like, "Didn't we just
talk about this last week?" He's like,
"Yeah, well, you know, deadline this
week." And it's like, "Right." So, the
deadline is throwing you off the
process. This is sort of like one of
those uh I think it's who is it, the
Navy Seals or the Marines is like
um slow is smooth and smooth is fast.
It's like if you would just like
spend two hours bulleting out your your
swipe, you can write the whole thing in
like an hour.
>> You'll go faster by doing it the slow
way. Yeah. You got to just trust that.
>> Exactly. And they get frazzled and they
start skipping steps and they fill in
the blanks with their brain and we know
how I feel about that.
>> Yeah. Well, I think it's I think it's
good points. So, over the last year,
I've seen something I've never seen
before. copyriters and marketers,
they're making more money than ever
before, especially the top 1%. And if
you want to be one of them [snorts] and
you want to join us and you want to get,
you know, insights into exactly what's
happening in our industry and also get
my raw and unfiltered thoughts, the
stuff that we're not sharing here on
YouTube, then apply to join my email
list at list.copyrightiting.org.
And uh yeah, I'll see you in my next
email. Now, let's get back to the video.
You know where it comes from for me is a
lot of the gurus that teach
copyrightiting that have made a couple
thousand dollars for an agency once and
they use the agency's templates and now
they know how to do it
>> and then copyriters start taking
templates out of context and just
slapping on to any sort of offer or they
have like a
they have the toolkit but not the
process
>> the context
>> you know. Yeah. Right. So it's like yeah
I get I get it. A lot of carpenters will
go and write an email or they'll do
research and they're like, "Oh yeah, I
got a research um prompt."
>> Do you have like a research process?
Because you seem to be pretty big on
research. Like how would you tell people
to do it?
>> I would say the biggest thing for me
with research, I'm not in the financial
space. So I think that the amount of
time I study the market is a little
different. Like with health copy, like
weight loss and info products, I spend a
little bit more time, I would say, on
understanding who I'm talking to than um
than I do on on like market research. In
a new niche, I spend a lot more time on
the market research cuz I don't know.
But like bisop for example, I know I
know the I know the customer pretty
well. So I would say like that biggest
thing for me is get on the phone with
the customer. The reason I think that's
important is that they don't want to do
it. So, if you can get them to do the
research they don't want to do,
>> it's a lot easier to like if you're
willing to get on the phone with a lady
in her like late 30s that's struggling
to lose weight and you're willing to sit
and like have empathy and actually talk
to her for 30 minutes. I think then
you're going to be you're going to find
it quite easy to literally go look at
all the other sales letters and other
promotional materials in the in the
niche and like extract what you want
from it because then you have this
reference point like this is the
customer, this is what her experiences
and you can look at all that promotional
material and say like she this is what
she sees and you can almost look at it
through her through her eyes for a
second.
>> Yeah. You can you could be like you
could like start looking at other sales
letters and you be like Sheila doesn't
need this [__] Like this doesn't
resonate with Sheila.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. I mean like for
example I was reviewing a beauty copy
like um some product you rub on your
face and it does your foundation for
you. And there's all these guys writing
this thing
>> and they all send me this copy and it's
like why are we why are we doing all
this logic mechanism stuff here? Like
why are we talking about all these
mechanisms? They literally just are t
like everybody knows that it's hard to
find foundation for your exact skin tone
>> and this thing solves it. Like let's
just get straight into demonstrative.
>> Everybody knows that.
>> Just show
>> today I learned,
>> right? But like in that niche they know,
right? In that niche they know that this
is like frustrating for them. So instead
of spinning like don't you hate when you
have to this and isn't it frustrating if
you have to this and doesn't it like
this is why don't you just start the ad
on Facebook? Can I try finally a
foundation that matches your skin tone?
Like could it just be like
>> just start there,
>> right? Like that's that's like the main
and then how you articulate that you can
create variation, right? But a lot of
these guys in that niche were just going
straight into this like problem agitate
and like the the real reason that you
don't have this is that you're missing
that. I'm like you're missing the point
here. Like you're taking this like just
start with the this me just this is a
physical product that you can visually
show. Why don't we just skip all that
fluff and just go straight to the
demonstration that this is a cool
product and works on their face?
>> I don't want to defend those writers,
but I can get it. Like when you come in
like uh so I remember
reading and watching YouTube videos
before doing uh before I got hired at
Agora. So, and I've got a lot of really
like
what do I want to say like defining
moments
>> that like changed the course the
trajectory of everything that I wish
more people I wish I could get this
message to everybody. I walked in. So,
do you know the 16word sales letter of
Aldo Albuquerque?
>> That was my copy chief.
>> And as far as I know, I was like the
first full-time junior he ever hired.
So, I walk in Delray Beach, like right
around the corner from here. And I'm,
you know, I want to do a good job. I
want to be successful. I want to be
like, you know, very competitive. I want
to be the best. I was the best like
sales guy on the phone at like my
previous job. And I tell him, I said,
"Hey, man. I read the Boron letters, the
AdWee copywriting handbook, and I read
uh Dan Kennedy's ultimate sales letter.
What else do I need to read?" And then
Aldo said, "Stop. That's enough. Don't
read about copy. Just read copy here."
And then like he basically like showed
me how to get promotions.
>> And uh it's like that goes all the way
back to us about 531. Like everything
there's that context now. Like one of
the things that I don't want someone
doing, this is something I found myself
trapped in was like googling the
internet. That's what I called it. Like
when you don't have an idea, you're just
googling the internet. Where's the idea?
And you're just looking at the whole
internet.
>> So you need a box.
>> David Deutsch says thinking inside the
box. He actually did like a idea
generation thing for the copy squad and
that was the presentation title I think
and either title or as title of a slide.
But I remember that line thinking inside
the box like exactly because I don't
want to be googling the internet. I knew
the problem. The solution is thinking
inside a box. How do you develop the
box? Well, you sort of got to know the
the stadium, the the game that you're
playing. And you do that by okay, I got
a foundation product.
>> Yeah.
>> So, even I think again I think the idea
of researching the customer, you know,
probably the most purest what do you
call it? First person or first primary
source material you can get. If you
can't, if you're like a freelancer or
whatever, for for whatever reason you
can't, the next best thing you could do
is go read the most successful
foundation promotions. To your point,
let me jump in here and quickly say
something. I think that reading that
promotion first is even better because
then you can go to those calls with
insights on how it's done, right?
>> True.
>> 100% with you. Like
>> like reading proven copy that people
have spent millions of dollars
promoting, it's like working and people
are buying. You've already they sold
like this is not a new you don't have to
solve a problem.
>> Now here's here's your first objection.
Well, how do I find the good copy? How
do I find the one that worked?
[laughter]
>> Yeah.
>> Tell us tell us how do you do it?
>> How do you find it?
>> How do I find it? How do I find the good
copy? How do I know this this
foundation?
>> First of all, if I had a client that's
making a lot of money, I'd probably just
ask my client like first of all, who are
the people in this market? That's one
way I would do it. If you know how to
find clients like and you're good at
prospecting, then you should be able to
find those businesses, how else would
you do it?
>> Do you have some ideas? Yeah.
>> Me?
>> Yeah.
>> Honestly, like short answer is
Instagram. Um, so I mean like I feel
like there's a million ways to do it and
I know there are people with really
sophisticated strategies about like
going to their Facebook page, finding
like how many like there's tools that
tell you how many impressions, how many
views, how many like you can get all
this deep deep information. For me, I I
actually need to be on Instagram more. I
don't check it every few days. But if
you do the stories, if you look at the
stories and you swipe, you're going to
get served ads.
>> Yeah. Yeah. because I am
I only have like three hobbies. Like I'm
usually getting served. Financial
publishing ads, I'm usually getting
served. And so all I got to do is be on
Instagram sort of like daily and over
the course of a week to two weeks. If
that ad is still bugging me by the time
I'm annoyed by it, that's a working ass.
And so what I do is I just click the ad
and then I take the URL like I open it
in my Google Chrome browser on my phone.
I send it to myself in a note. I open it
on my laptop and I save the PDF and
that's it. Now I've got a list of like
all the next promos I'm going to be
breaking down. That's another thing.
I've been doing this for almost a
decade. Um, and I I've
helped produce upwards $60 million in
revenue.
>> I still break down. I do not get to this
point where it's like, I got it.
>> Yeah.
>> Now I can just use that brain of mine.
Now I can just make [__] up because I've
I've done it so many times. If my back
was against the wall and someone, you
know, threatened my family or something
and said, "You got to have this written
by tomorrow." I could, but
I still go through the 531. I'm going
through it right now. I literally today,
so I just had to pack up an old filing
cabinet and move it.
>> And I found like my original draft from
like my first year at Agora. And I found
what I used to do before I had like PDFs
and this big massive swipe file on my
computer. I would print the promotions
cuz I had a industrial grade like a Gora
printer. I could print like two pages
and I could do like uh two pages per
sheet front and back and I could have
like a whole promotion in like 20 pages
and I'd print them and I'd mark them up.
And so I'm moving all of these boxes and
boxes of files. And the way that I used
to do it is I'd have like the manila
folder and then inside you'd have three
or four promotions and the binder clips
would sort of separate the promotions
and that would be like this folder
represented my first front end. This
folder represented my first backend.
This folder represented a read lead I
was writing this folder and then I was
going through it. Some of the folders I
had the same promotion printed out and
marked up. Meaning I read that promo for
this project and then I marked it up.
The next project that was similar, I had
reprinted the same one. I knew it was
good and I had worked on the first one I
did
>> and it was in there again,
>> reprinted and marked up again for the
next time I needed to do a similar uh
project. So, it's like
>> I don't think that shit's like locked in
here forever. There are things that I
can now
kind of spit out like we are in a way
like AI. Like I've sort of like got this
habit, this pattern of language that I
call like that's I call copywriting a
language. It's
>> I learned this because I I went to
school I got a masters in accounting and
they called accounting the language of
business.
>> You if you can speak accounting and read
the numbers and debits and credits, you
speak the language of business. And so I
carried that when I started learning
copies. I like this is the language of
sales.
>> They say it's salesmanship and print
>> but it is a language. I can go into it
like someone when like we're in Florida.
People can go in and out of Spanish
here, you know, like they can just start
speaking English and like oh turn to
their de they madre and start speaking
in Spanish and then come right back to
you in English and uh I can do that with
copy. I can start like uh and again it
comes back to ideas four punches, right?
>> So like if I wanted to drop like a cred
section, you know, there's a couple
things that I can do. I can do like a
resume run. You know, I got my start at
Agora in 2017. Put out $7.1 million in
my first year. They recruited me up to
Wealthpress. Made Copy Chief within the
first year. Took a team about a dozen
writers of 50 million. Decided to go
out, start my own agency. Been doing
that for the last couple years. I've
been training writers. I got my first
couple writers to like my first writer
to a million dollar in royalties back in
the day. Blah blah. And I I have this
resume run I can do. I can do what I
call career highlights. And career
highlights is like
would be it's a snippet of something
great that you did. So it would be like,
you know, I had one promotion make $15
million. Um I had like, you know, a the
kid that I a 20-year-old junior writer I
took in his first year to a million
dollars of royalties. Um I took a VP at
a trucking company, pulled him out of
his career and surpassed his old salary
as a copywriter on my team. These are
little things you can do. Um, I can do
uh IP, intellectual property. Uh, I can
do like so like IP published works kind
of thing, you know. You know, I'm pretty
well known for my book Take Their Money.
It's where I I first reveal like the
language of sales and the big four
selling emotions, but I also have, you
know, some pretty famous courses and
frameworks like the beasts of a sales
letter and my YouTube channel where I've
got, you know, I don't know, 20,000
subscribers or something like that. Um,
and then so what's another one? rubbed
elbows with. Here we are. Mark Ford's um
art
>> museum gallery.
>> Museum. Yeah. Like we're we're gonna
have we're gonna have cigars with Mark
and Sean, a bunch of other copywriters
tonight. You know, gonna have a big
mastermind tomorrow. A lot of uh cool
speakers. Uh there's who's who has been
invited. This name, this name, this
name.
>> Uh what's another one you can do? You
can do big predictions. big predictions
probably not going to be as impactful in
like uh copyrightiting like I called
like that this was going to happen or
something like that.
>> Yeah.
>> But so yeah, so it's again when I talk
about the four punches like when I when
I come at a technique I'm not making it
up. I know that I'm gonna when I do a
resume run I'm going to talk about yeah
>> this is it's like your LinkedIn profile
spoken like first I did this I went here
and when you're doing your resume run
what big company logos can I attach to
my name you know what awards or
achievements so got my start at Agora
Financial back when it was a $300
million uh number one publisher in the
world
first year $7.1 million so you know you
borrow the credibility of the the logo
and the business brand. You throw in
your accolade. Then I say I got
recruited, right? So I didn't just go to
WealthPress. Someone came and poached me
from Agora, asked me to come work at
WealthPress and show them like the Agora
way
>> and I took that one. And so the beneath
the surface truth of it all is it takes
like a village, a a marketing team, a
great media buyer, a dedicated
publisher, a smart guru. But you know,
short version of that is I took that
company, right? They were doing 2
million when I got there. Two years, the
next year was 11. The next year we did
$50 million in sales. As the copy chief,
you can sort of I can attach myself to
that. So I can say like, you know, I
helped grow that business from two
million to 50. So I can say I helped
grow, which is true. I helped grow that
business two million to 50. I had about
a team a team of about a dozen writers.
I did take several writers who were
green, like their first promos to their
first million-doll promotion and gurus.
I took some gurus their first
million-dollar promotion. I paid out a
million dollars in royalties to one
writer. That was his cut. So, and this
is a guy in his 20s in his first year
doing it. He made a million dollars, not
produced a million, made. So, um, again,
like what's important to note here is
what I was leading to is that people
will say, "I'm creative." People will
say like, "How'd you come up with that?"
That's just a jab, baby.
>> That's just a hook. Like, that's that's
a [__] cross. Like that's just
there's I didn't invent that. You know,
Floyd Mayweather has been doing that for
a gazillion years. Like it's it's just
what copy is. And again, like you can
sort of maneuver yourself in and out of
that that language and that flow.
>> Yeah. Yeah. If you understand what I'm
doing is just conjugation,
you know,
>> like necess
I I just understand like these are this
is the information about me that I have
>> and I am simply, you know, yeah, you
could just call it conjugation or I'm
making the tenses match the subject.
Like it's it's just um it's just making
it full. It's like instead of putting it
like filling in the blanks, you're
filling in the you're you're
>> you're filling the ideas into a flow.
Yeah.
>> You know, it's actually the same thing I
did when I got started. I like that you
bring this up because fundamentally like
I have one system that I I share with my
my coaching clients. Like I build a
system called
>> break down the copy. And it's like
here's what you're looking for when you
look at other copy. Like break it down
by these like break down this section
and this section and this section and
this section. When I got my big break
with my first um multi-ight figure info
guru coach, they told me at the
beginning of um the probation period,
they're like, you know, we need you to
write 10 emails this week and just
expect only one of them to get approved,
you know, cuz it's not easy.
I just looked at all the copy out there
in that exact niche and I looked at the
the guru. I looked at the copy out there
and I went and I don't think I printed
it although I may have printed it but I
basically highlighted it maybe on a
Google doc or something and I was like
here's this section here's this section
here's this section um here's this
section and I like structured I was like
okay so for example with emails it's
like intriguing lead that pulls them in
with open loop some context to add some
more intrigue to the lead um and then
after that I would go into like let's
Okay, declare the opportunity, you know,
and then briefly back up why this is an
opportunity from an emotional standpoint
and then give them some proof points to
justify that that's emotional and then
give them an opportunity to take
advantage of it or something like this.
So that was like my highle flow of it
and I would write I wrote all 10, they
got all approved because I just focused
on that. So, like I think for
copywriters watching this, like the
biggest thing that you can take away
from, you know, from Kyle's experience
here and also my experience reviewing
copy is like we're not inventing stuff.
There's like everything I've ever
written has been written before in a
different format. I mean, there's maybe
ideas I took and made fresh and
synthesized stuff that's more relevant
today than before and it looks new, but
it's all really the same formats. I
don't like to say I really invented
personally. I didn't really invent much.
It's just it's just that structure. And
so it's like my research process is that
it's like you you know go and talk to
customers because if you can do the
hardest thing then you're kind of also
in the right headsp space. Go look at
all the proven stuff that's made money.
Break that down. Why does it work? And
truly break it down. Then you don't need
like most copy critique. Most of the
critique I'm doing is one of those two
things.
>> That's funny though right there. One
thing that I want I've been trying to
think of how to just say it without
interrupting you. You're talking about
talking to customers, getting on the
phone. Do you know I mean I'm sure you
do. How many writers begin writing
without even having looked at the
product or even know who the guru is?
Like
>> they're already writing. It's like
I
I don't even know where to start with
that one. you you literally haven't
talked to the guy that whose voice
you're going to write in.
They I I honestly think part of that
comes from the hammock thing. Like go
sit on a beach and write in a hammock.
>> Yeah. This is a guru it's just guru
messaging telling them this is how it
should be like just chill.
>> And but the thing is that attracts this
people who
I
they're like scared of other people.
>> Yeah. like they thought, "Oh, well, I'm
an introvert, meaning I'm not maybe not
very assertive and I'm shy or I don't
want to look silly. I can I can kind of
hide behind the screen and I can be
having a pinina colada like while I do
it and making apparently $100,000 a
year." And uh it's like
it's still
so again like the idea that
copyrightiting is a professional
language.
>> You know there's an operating word there
professional.
Like you can make more money than a
lawyer. You can make more money than a
doctor. But do you think those dudes
ain't after it? Do you like you still
like the money still has to be like
earned?
>> Yeah. That's a really really good way to
put it. It's like it's hard. You can
make that much, but there's a reason.
There's a process to that. It's not just
like Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> I mean, there's shitty lawyers. There's
shitty lawyers in podunk towns who make
nothing. And then there's like the dudes
who are on TV always representing the
worst humans alive and getting them out
of crimes. Like, so those guys are rich
as [__]
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Maybe there's, you know, not a moral
lesson there, but uh but yeah, that's
the thing.
And copy in the truest like if we're
going to be honest about it is a 991
game. There is there is a 1% of it's a
it's an exponential like curve like
this. It's not 8020.
>> It's 99 one 99% of them are making [__]
all like nothing.
>> Sad.
>> 1%. And the other thing is the 1% that's
making the money. I can speak from
personal experience and I think others
in this position would agree with me.
Once you're in the once you're a made
man, right? Once you're in the 1%. Then
it's a matter of the dial. If I want to
make 500 or a million or whatever, what
I do is I dial up the volume.
>> I have now the range to do it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Do I make it? Do I
make a million bucks a year right now?
No. Do I work at the milliondoll pace I
worked at Wealth Press? Definitely not.
But if I wanted it, I know
>> to dial things.
>> You just dial it. It's just dialing now.
>> The the 99 are kind of stuck. And I
think really the chasm is that the stuff
that we're talking about, the research
and the work, I would just call it the
process.
>> Yeah. So I was on a consulting call this
Thursday and I was teaching what was it
I was telling them basically breaking
down promos a four punch sort of thing.
So there's a technique I call big guys
pile in. All right so in financial
publishing big guys pile in it's a
credibility move and you usually use it
early like in the lead.
>> So I tell you there's an investment
let's say it's a new version of AI.
Okay, there's a new AI thing happening
and it's going to make you so rich. It's
going to just blow the pants off of all
the other money. Forget Nvidia. Like,
this is going to be 10 times bigger.
Okay, so right there, trigger
skepticism. As soon as you broke, like
that's it. I got them.
>> So, now you're saying [__]
>> So, my my actual process for a lead is
>> pattern interrupt, trigger BS,
credibility, demonstrations.
>> Yeah. So brilliant. A lot of writers are
too afraid, too insecure to actually
push.
>> I'll have writers write it backwards.
They'll start with the credibility in
the head and then they'll try. That's
>> big proof for it.
>> Yeah. [__] that. You got to come out and
you got to get them saying you got to
get them a little bit like no way, don't
believe that BS kind of thing. You want
to trigger the skepticism. So with the
big guys pilein idea. So with that, the
way this ties in, I've made my big
claim. I've triggered your skepticism. I
want to use big guys pile in to prove to
you it's real. And I'm gonna say that's
why Amazon has just dedicated a million
dollars to this. Microsoft
>> $20 million. Uh
>> who else is a big company? Tesla. You
know,
>> it's very fun.
>> All of those. So, we're throwing in the
big guys pile in, right? [laughter]
So, what I'm what I'm teaching my
consulting clients is this, you know,
this week, I want you to start looking
picking a technique, but I want you to
start trying to build out what I would
call texture. How can you add texture to
these? So, the worst version of big guys
pile in is the company and the dollar
amount. Amazon is in for a million,
Apple is in for 10 million, Meta is in
for 20, and Microsoft's in for 40.
>> There's no story behind that. That's the
worst. Yeah.
>> All right. Right. So there's no story
there.
>> So what you can do very easily is you
can do one, two, three of them and then
on the fourth one say Google's in for
100 million. The CEO said,
I quote, you know, our biggest fear was
underinvesting. We couldn't invest
enough.
>> There's like one layer of dimension in
texture, right? Likeing I just throw
that in there. Now there's a little bit
of a narrative and story like, wow, this
must be a big deal. M
>> um another way that you could add
texture to big guys pile in would be
like Amazon just dedicated a million to
build out six new data centers. Apple
just dedicated 10 million to hire an
entire team to develop this new
technology.
>> And so in order to right like I add that
so it's like they're dedicating specific
resources. They're in on this. They're
really, you know, and then if you can
find like a big one like, you know, an
and and Apple's jumping in with both
feet dedicating a whopping two billion
dollars to build out a whole, you know,
this and this and this. That's another
way. There's another way you could do
big guys pile in is you could do, you
know, the unexpected or unusual investor
or like what I call changed his tune. So
you could do this with like say for
gold. just like, you know, gold's been,
you know, he's in, he's in, he's in.
Even Warren Buffett, who said he hated
gold and never own it, now has $50
million worth of gold bricks, right?
>> So, you got the guy changed his tune,
which is like, wow, this must be a bit.
Remember, what I'm doing is I told you
this new thing is going to make you
rich. And you're like, [__]
>> And I'm like, no, seriously, look what
Apple's doing. Look what Amazon's doing.
Look at Microsoft. There's one more
um Oh, yeah. So, you can dimensionalize
it with texture. So I can go Apple,
Amazon, Microsoft are in for this much.
And it's not just them. Sovereign wealth
funds like from Japan, Saudi Arabia, and
even the US government is investing
through NASA blah blah blah blah blah.
So I can dimensionalize. It's not just
them. It's also this other cluster of
authorities giving it texture, making it
feel like, wow, this must be a big.
That's what we're always trying to get
them to say. Wow, this must be a big
deal, right? Must be real. So, what I
was teaching the clients was find like
break down promos every [__] day. And
I'll tell you what Joe taught us at
Agora was the daily practice is read a
piece of copy, write a piece of copy,
come up with an idea every day. So,
you're automatically doing it. That's a
given. I told him, find a technique. And
I said, now look, I've been doing it for
like a decade every day. So, it's like
my repository is very deep. Do not put
the burden on yourself to have every
technique this week. I don't want to
hear you come to the next call and say,
"I figured out every possible way to do
a better than section." Well, no. I I
want you to start building
ways to texturize it. I want you to
start putting different arrows in your
quiver. And that means you have to
approach it with the duality, the
dichotomy of like urgency. I need to do
this, but the patience to know I'm going
to do this every day forever.
>> Yeah.
>> Until I die, I'm going to be I'm going
to be acrewing more and more of these
techniques. And so that's like you have
to approach it with that sort of this is
the thing I was saying the process.
>> This is what writers do. You have to
identify as a writer. That's not like
you're not you're not doing this
project. You're a writer and every day
you sit down and you go through your
process and over time you will have this
big repository of technique and everyone
will be like, "Wow, you're so creative."
And it's like all the stuff I just laid
out for you has come from thousands of
repetitions.
That's just I was like wrote memory what
we just did. It wasn't creativity.
>> Yeah.
>> You know what I mean? So that's my
spirit. Well, I mean this is uh to your
point like with with email copy um every
sing literally every single time I write
a new format in a new niche anywhere
it's like how do I go and get 5 10 15 20
examples of how that's done right cuz
somebody's paying those copyriters just
like from a besides the performance of
how it actually does
>> those businesses were happy with that to
the point where they put money behind it
and they put it out into the world. So
there's a good chance that if you can
ride like that, you're at least slotting
in at the same level as everybody else
that's getting paid. So like if I'm
going to go write something in I mean
this has been a big thing with a lot of
copies are talking about like ecom DTOC
>> and like all these new static ads that
people need to come up with and you know
creative strategy is a big word in the
in the industry at the moment.
>> Just go look at what these guys are
producing and be like can I do that?
Yeah. Just like break down why does it
work? How does it work? um you know what
techniques are they using? Break down
the different ideas. Break down the
different formats. Choose a few. Choose
five. So over the last year, I've seen
something I've never seen before.
Copyriters and marketers, they're making
more money than ever before, especially
the top 1%. And if you want to be one of
them, [snorts] and you want to join us,
and you want to get, you know, insights
into exactly what's happening in our
industry, and also get my raw and
unfiltered thoughts, the stuff that
we're not sharing here on YouTube, then
apply to join my email list at
list.copyrighting.org.
And uh yeah, I'll see you in my next
email. Now, let's get back to the video.
>> The problem is they're so excited or
eager to start tapping on those keys,
man.
>> Yeah.
>> Like what you're saying right here, I
think everyone will hear it, but they
won't listen. They'll hear like, "Oh,
yeah, just break down this and this and
this." So, what they'll do is they'll be
like, "Okay, I found five." And
now they're in on the writing. It's
like, "Did they actually sit down?
>> Print it and take a highlighter and like
study it." telling you like I'm not
disagreeing with you, but like I don't
know where somewhere in that process
they just short circuit it. They're just
like, "Well,
I'm bored." Like, "I'm going to just
start writing." Like they don't actually
like it has that's again with the 531
process. You'll read it five, you'll
read five, you'll go back and bullet
three of them. I really like this
process. You'll read it twice at that
point. That's gonna for some people it's
be boring, but you're going to be
reading it very deliberately. You're not
just a passive reader. You're looking at
what is the claim,
>> where are the claims, and what pieces of
proof did they use? And since you're
reading a relevant promotion with a
similar offer and mechanism, you'll be
like, "Oh, [__] I can say the same [__]
about my mechanism. I can frame my
mechanism the exact same way. My
mechanism works just as fast, actually
faster. I can use this claim all day."
So, but again, it's it's the repetition
that makes it muscle memory that makes
it feel so natural and like, "Oh, you're
so creative." That kind of stuff comes
from the ability to just and it sounds
natural because it's just again, it's
the muscle memory of it all. It's
throwing It's throwing the perfect jab,
throwing the perfect cross. Like, I've
thrown that many. Now, I can do it. And
it looks It's like an Olympic athlete.
They always make their sport look almost
like dull. Like they're so good at it.
Like the it it's so dialed and so
perfect. You're like, "Oh, all I got to
do is get on those two bars and like
swing my legs around and do like a
handstand. Easy. I just watched that guy
do it a hundred times." Like,
>> yeah,
>> that's like good copy often looks. Okay,
here's we can we can move on the next
section after this like one line. I know
like copy is like killer and all the
best copy would here's how it would
always happen when something got big
enough that people started talking about
it and like the operations and like
email manager or like some sort of like
non-copy related pro position like
marketing calendar I don't know
something when they would eventually get
hold of it because it made like 10
million bucks and then they'd look at it
and then they'd say like I don't know
why I do all this I should just write
copy
When they say it like that, like all he
does is just say, you know, you can make
a million bucks in a day. It's like
that's like the best promotion.
>> Yeah.
>> The best promotion is where
>> cuz Oh my god, I'm going to get on a
rant, but like the
>> the copyriters who get in their own way,
they tie their shoelaces together. It's
because they feel like their mechanism
isn't clever enough. Their force of
nature, the force of nature is always
something stupid.
>> It's literally something like gravity.
>> [laughter]
>> It's always something like it's just
like it's why I like to use the word
force of nature. It's like the wind
blowing. Oh, tsunami.
>> Most of the time when you hear about
these opportunities, they use natural
language. It's a title wave of wealth.
It's a tsunami of cash. It's a windfall.
It's like a hurricane. It's a disaster.
That's so true.
>> It's chaos. It's They always use this
kind of language. It's And it's always
like um there's a small cap company that
hopefully gets FDA approval. Like that's
like the whole thing. Like [laughter]
and every time a small cap company gets
FDA approval, it blows up like it did
with Ozmpic, like it did with Wiggoi,
like it did with all these other things.
Look it. Boom, boom, boom, boom. And
this time if it happens, you're going to
get so rich. So, um, but they think that
that's too obvious and they they throw
her away
>> and they miss out on the chance to
basically make a gazillion dollars.
>> I love it. This is this has been uh this
has been fantastic. It's been a master
class on breaking down copy,
researching, getting out of your own
way, and then
writing a lot of stuff and making a
bazillion dollars.
>> Yeah, you got to make a bazillion
dollars.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's important. So, with
that said, there's a reason we have
these laptops here. We're actually going
to do something special today. We're
going to be reviewing a little bit of
copy live and well, recorded live and
we're going to just be like uh I guess
applying the same stuff. So, uh let's
get into it. Okay. So, Kyle, I got some
copy here from some of the copyrightism
coaching. Let's have a look at this
first video sales letter. It's VSSL and
I'd love to get your thoughts on this
one.
>> All right, cool. So this one is about
the million or more saved. This is
important for anyone ever getting copy
like it has to be an anti- ego thing
where and this goes back to the idea of
like don't think do the least like your
personal [__] cannot get mixed in the
copy and when I'm critiquing copy if I'm
berating the [__] out of the copy I'm
critiquing the copy. I'm criti I'm I am
critiquing the words on this page and
the order that they are presented
not you you know this is not you're a
dumbass that this is the copy isn't
working for me because of these reasons.
>> Yeah.
>> And I think that like that's has to be
if I you know if you don't already know
that you have to understand that that's
the nature of the game like you get
better through course correction like
through the like it's like bumper rails
on a bowling alley. Like you get better
from bumping against the rail until you
hit a strike, not from just driving
straight down the middle, which is what
everyone would like it to be is smooth
down the middle strike, but it's really
more like bouncing off the rails.
>> But you have to be able to be that. I
think like to your point with critique,
you have to be brutal because otherwise
you get too attached to the writing as a
writer. This is one of the things I like
when my coach was critiquing me like
really rough. I could hear the voice. It
helped me disassociate from the copy.
So, I could just see the copy for words
on the page and then you can actually
like look at it objectively instead of
like, oh yeah, it's kind of nice. Like
just just keep reading and you'll see
what I'm you see you'll see why it's
good, you know? Because I' i've had that
where I'm like, I don't get this. This
doesn't make sense. Like, no, no, no,
just keep reading, you know?
>> Yeah. Well, that's the point. Yeah. I
would stop reading. Yeah. Exactly. So, I
got to tell this story. One time I was
roped into a copy competition like
non-consensually.
So, I was at WealthPress and um Connor
the publisher and Rob the other
copywriter set up a copyrighting
competition. And then when the
submissions came in, like all 84 of
them, they decided that I was going to
be the judge after, oh [__] Kyle will
figure it out. And I did actually, which
is, but here's how I did it is I just
read the first four lines of all of them
>> because I knew what has to happen in the
first four lines. What ended up
happening is I had to pick three
winners. I could only pick two because I
wanted to see what's in it for me in the
first four lines. I need to know why
we're here, why you're talking to me in
four lines. And if I didn't, I would
exit. So that made my whole review
process very quick. I got through them
all and I could only find two winners. I
had to go back and extend it to six
lines. Oh,
>> to find the third winner because nobody
would just get to the point in four
lines. So, jumping into this one, let's
read this first one. If you have 1
million or more saved and you are
worried about running out of money in
retirement, then this might be the most
important financial presentation you
ever see. Fine. I mean, like, we getting
right into it. We know why we're here.
Look at this. So, there's like a visual
pattern interrupt. Take a look at this.
Look at this. Recently, economists from
Stanford University and the
International Monetary Fund published
research that proved some wealthy people
earn returns that are up to 18
percentage points higher on the same
types of investments as everyone else.
Okay, so if you are in or nearing
retirement with 1 million or more saved,
you need to pay close attention. And
here's why.
Okay. So, right here, I feel like I've
got a couple pieces of feedback. Again,
the first line, so when it comes to
pattern interrupt, so we talked about
this, my formula is pattern interrupt,
trigger BS,
>> credibility.
>> I love that one. Yeah.
>> Uh, and demonstrate results. You can
swap like some people go straight into
the results and then drop credit after.
But those four things need to happen
first before anything else. So, is there
a pattern interrupt? I would say sure.
or it calls out the audience says, "You
need to pay attention."
Immediately it says, "Economists from
Stanford University and the
International Monetary Fund published
research. Some wealthy people earn
returns up to 18% higher on the same
investments." So, it's like we were just
talking about running out of money
the and having a million saved. The next
line needs to be this thing makes
thousands of dollars a month for anyone
with a million bucks like enough to live
on like 5,000 a month with this. So the
next thing needs to be you need to tie
those into some sort of mechanism or
opportunity
>> force of nature. It needs to be recently
Stanford University found a special type
of investment for folks over $1 million
in net worth that could
allow them to continually not only
generating income into retirement but
continually growing their wealth even as
they're spending it.
>> I like that line. Yeah.
>> So, you need to go with something that's
in this first line, the million dollars
and the running out of money thing. So,
I tied both of those in. But then also I
need to introduce something new. So
there is something new sort of. As soon
as he said some wealthy people earn
returns,
you start to lose me. 18 percentage
points higher on the same types of
investments. We got what I call double
mumbo jumbo. All right. That means
you've introduced two veiled concepts
that I don't fully understand in one
line. Some wealthy people earn returns.
It's too vague on 18 percentage points
higher on the same types of investments
as everyone else.
There's too much happening right there
and none of it's concrete. A
>> lot of cognitive load to process that
stuff,
>> right?
>> I do like what what did they do good?
They called out the audience um and they
use credible sources Stanford and the
IMF right out of the gate to say this is
real. What they didn't do a good job of
is locking down a concrete mechanism or
opportunity.
And by doing that, they would solve the
second problem, which is I need to know
there's some sort of new mechanism, new
way, new discovery, new opportunity.
And they did say recently they published
research, which is kind of a hint at
new, but it gets lost in all the other
stuff. And so again, like we were
talking about this earlier, like if if
this is broken, there's no power word I
can give you on the next couple lines.
There's no like it the the source the
the roots are too shallow. The tree will
fall over, whatever the hell you want to
call it. So there's nothing I really do
beyond that. I will say though, here's
why. This barrage of questions after
this would be one of those things where
I would say like, you wrote this. Why
the [__] is this right here?
>> I would be like, unless you can show me
in all your swipes, they always have a
barrage of questions at this moment.
This seems very foreign to me. Like, and
again, that I I usually only review
financial promos. Um, but I don't I
can't recall one successful promo that
I've reviewed in the last 10 years that
gave me five backto-back questions on
line five.
>> That doesn't make any sense. Where did
that come from? It doesn't fit the the
again, if I picture myself as like an
AI, all the knowledge bank and database
that my AI would be pulling from my
brain, this would never be produced.
Nothing resembles this in any of my my
AI database. So that would be like the
next thing
>> you reckon maybe like this kind of ideas
when I look at this it looks like an
idea that maybe someone would put in a
lead like like one or two questions at
the beginning of a lead but now we've
got like almost a double like the idea
behind this is to double pull attention
but it's like it's we got better idea at
the beginning already so it's just
>> fluff I um here's the other thing that I
I predict is happening is this is um I
would guess that this is insecure
copywriting. And what I mean by that is
they didn't feel secure that their hook
was hookie enough and so they just threw
five more hooks and one of them is
repeat.
>> Compensation copy is what I call it.
>> What do you call it?
>> Compensation copy.
>> Compensation. Yeah, it's what it is.
It's insecure. So, you're
overcompensating. My hook wasn't strong
enough. What about this? What about
>> I feel like it's not enough, but let me
throw more stuff
>> instead of just going back to the the
main thing and making it better.
>> Right. So every line from there on, like
what I was saying on the first line,
we're talking about a million bucks
saved and running out of money. The next
line needs to be about that. And then
the line after that has to expand on it,
and the next one has to expand on that.
And this is a thumbtack thing that I
imagine in my head is I need to be able
to put a thumb tack in one of the
concepts, wrap a string around it, and I
need to be able to pull it to the next
one. And I need to be able to do that
from each sentence to the next. If ever
I need to break that string, you wasted
my time as a reader. it wasn't important
enough to elaborate on or be the focus.
And in the first four lines when we do
breakdowns, like so in my copy squad
group, we do breakdowns every Tuesday.
I spend if we do a new sales letter, I
spend 30 minutes probably on the
headline and like 30 minutes like the
first six lines. I spend like an hour
before I even get into the copy
>> because it's right now what we're doing.
We could talk about these first six
lines for the next hour.
>> Um but that's because they're that
important. you're setting the stage
right now. I need to know why we're here
and I have to make the decision. So, if
like you mentioned someone submitted
copy in like a dating program, right?
So, if you're doing pick up and dating
stuff like there's there's a direct
approach and an indirect approach. If
you do a direct approach, you walk up,
you say, "Hey, I think you're pretty."
Well, then the girl has to make a
decision right there. Like she's already
been like sort of propositioned and
she's like, "Okay, I have to make a
decision right now. I can't really get
more information. I can't really decide
if I like your personality or like
you're basically saying choose and she's
just probably going to opt to no. She's
just say no. It's like the easy way out.
Um so it's like if if you aren't giving
me something in the lead right away, if
you make it so easy for me like it's too
confused. I don't know if this is for
me. I don't know. And what you can do is
just make it so damn appealing that you
like they don't have to do this five
questions like would this work? Would
this work? Would this work? That's
really what it is is like you got to
make it so appealing. And the way that
you would do that is be like sure it's
only going to talk to people over a
million bucks, which is a small small
segment, but basically make it like one
of the things that I said was like, you
know, not only will it sustain your
income and sustain your lifestyle as a
net worth over a million person, you'll
actually grow your wealth.
>> I like that idea,
>> right? So, it's like, oh [__] Well, a
billionaire wants a millionaire likes
wealth. They're going to want to know
how to sustain that lifestyle and grow
it. I mean, okay, tell me more. And and
what really more realistically is going
to happen than, okay, tell me more is
[__] I know all the different
investments
>> cuz I'm a millionaire.
>> Yeah. And you'll be like, "Look, that's
why Stanford University just published
new research saying, you know, XYZ." And
now the International Monetary Fund,
something way bigger than even
universities or scholastic journals is
digging in on this too. Like there you
go. Big guys piling in kind of stuff.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I like that idea.
Yeah. There you go. From earlier. Same
job.
>> Yeah.
>> And the way that the texture of it. So
again, like you'll say something I I I
use the word like even the International
Monetary Fund, you know, they're not
just like dabbling in research. They're
So, okay, here's another big guys pile
in or credibility. So, if we're doing
pattern interrupt, trigger BS,
credibility.
I just sort of did it on accident. And
again, it wasn't because I was creative.
It was because of muscle memory.
Hey, if you're a millionaire and you
worry about running out of money,
there's a brand new type of investment
that dominates, destroys other
investments, not only will it sustain
your lifestyle, it actually grow your
wealth into retirement. Stanford
University has already published
research on this and even the
International Monetary Fund. Now, here's
the next thing, comma. I would say
something like
uh literally uh I'd say the
International Monetary Fund, the group I
would give it I would So, here's what
you could do. You could say Stanford
University, one of the most respected
economics schools in the blah blah blah
in the country said this this this this.
So, notice that
Stanford's credible, but I would texture
texture. I'd add layers. I'd say
Stanford University,
home of one of the most uh respected
economics schools in in the country,
comma, has researched deeply into this
and found this, you know, f find that
from their abstract on the journal, this
outperforms virtually every asset class.
Even then I see now when I want to add
something, I don't want to just be like
and this and this and this and this.
What I would add for IMF is I'd say even
the International Monetary Fund,
responsible for I don't know what they
do. So maybe they're responsible for
dictating monetary policy has
>> concluded colon something cool about
this asset class.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Boom. Right there.
>> None of your own words. It's all just
taken from what they're already saying
in previous promos.
>> And and the other thing, dude, like I
didn't make any of that up. I know the
structure. I did it with the research.
Everything I said came off of a Google
doc that, you know, I looked at the IMF
website. I looked at Stanford. I copied
it. I pasted it, you know, like I this
these are all facts.
>> It's all research. It's not my
creativity.
>> The only creative thing I did was how do
I make it fit the structure, which also
wasn't creative. The structure was the
structure. Pattern interrupt, trigger,
BS, cred, and then demo results.
>> So, how would I demo results for
something like this? I didn't read past
this, but you could say something like,
you know, Carl Icon has already um
jumped all over. This is also big guys
pile in has already jumped into this to
>> jumped in
>> has jumped in to add another $10 million
to his hedge funds bottom line. And Bill
Aman went on record to publicly say like
he's putting in another gazillion
dollars or something like that. And my
one of my my good friends Another little
social.
>> My good friend Warren Buffett has
already brought in a billion dollars
thanks to Oh, check it out. My good
friend,
Warren Buffett, the Oracle of Omaha, one
of the most And here's the thing, you
have to tie it to this thing. So you'd
say my good friend Warren Buffett,
one of the wealthiest
men in, you know, what I want to say is
like he's wealthy and maintaining his
lifestyle.
>> Right. One of the most conservative I
want to stress, remember we're always
speaking in new, easy, safe, and big.
>> Yeah.
>> So I want to stress my good friend
Warren Buffett. I'm rubbing shoulders
with Warren one comma and I give him
credibility just like I said Stanford
one of the most prestigious economic
schools Warren Buffett comma one of the
most conservative safest most reliable
investing experts in the world has and I
give the result put 10 billion dollar uh
into Birkshshire Haway accounts thanks
to this new investment.
So when I say that he's the most
conservative, I'm leaning into this idea
of this isn't risky. Warren Buffett,
he's the most conservative out there and
he's the smartest. You think some id
like do you think Warren Buffett's dumb?
Like do you cuz he's already making
money off this? What are you doing?
>> It's brilliant.
>> And so we're on what line four.
>> Yeah. Amazing. Yeah.
>> Do you have any [__] question about
what we're here to talk about and why
it's useful for you? That's what I'm
talking about. Get to the point. And
people like, well, there's so much to
say. It's like, no, there isn't.
>> You pattern interrupt, trigger BS,
credibility, demo, result. Then you can
go into
>> pattern interrupt, trigger BS,
credibility, demo,
>> demo result. Then you can go into things
like expand the opportunity. You can go
into like teasing, and you can go into
all these other techniques. They're all
just different forms of, you know, jab,
cross, hook, and uppercut. So, um I know
that we were going to like blast through
a couple of these, but I really think
like sitting here and like no matter
which one we look at, if they remember
what we just, you know, the the four
steps or whatever, and they understand
like that this is the approach, it
doesn't matter how many of these we look
at, I'm going to have basically the same
answer. And I what will change is like
how would I how would I manifest that as
copy for that particular offer or
opportunity. But um yeah, I think w with
just one of these and the things that we
just covered, I think that that can be
like universally applicable.
>> Cool. Let's take a look at this other
one here. So you see this uh weird
business models minting millionaires at
record speeds one.
>> So I like this patent interrupt as the
subject line. I feel like when I read
the body copy here, we kind of missed
that. Like we had such a nice subject
line for that. It's a little long
actually, but if that was the first
sentence,
we kind of like a little bit of that
that big idea there, you know? So, if
there was a way to maybe say it in a
similar way in the lead here, like
instead of saying, "Hey, first name, a
recent entrepreneur article revealed
this the weird actually I would say this
weird type of business." Um, but the
weird business is minting millionaires
at record speeds in 2025 and 2026. I
feel like that's the credibility that we
can bring and if we were to follow that
same format that you were saying which
is like pat pattern interrupt trigger BS
then throw this credibility in I would
say something like hey first name
um maybe whatever the the target
demographic is here like you know a lot
of people are looking at you know making
money with AI these days but like the
real the real players in this space are
can, you know, five even 10 times more
than these AI guys with the most boring
business you probably never heard of
like trigger something like this and
then then you would go into maybe this
article like and entrepreneur.com.
>> And I think one thing too like like uh
one thing that works really well there
is like surprising fact.
>> Yeah. like the thing that you just said
like you know it's it's sort of like the
example like this is the fastest thing
>> or if you had that like concrete data
point that you could throw at them.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I like it. So like I would I
would probably figure out like this
entrepreneur article. Can we go a little
bit deeper? It's like there's there's
it's missing it's missing context. Like
what about the entrepreneur article?
this the you know this author or this
expert featured on entrepreneur.com you
know blah blah blah like add some
context there as well. I don't write
much financial copy, so I think riffing
it's going to be difficult for me. But
what I can say is this is definitely
missing like a big promise on the lead.
Like I don't really know why I should be
reading this.
>> And I'm also not particularly sure why I
should have a boring business. And I
think a lot of people in in biz bisop
and B2B
>> um with coaching, it's always like a lot
of copyriters assume that having or
wanting that people want a business.
They don't want a business. They want to
make money. They don't want to like
build a business. That sounds like work.
It's like, oh, you got to build a
business.
>> My friend, this is this is a little
dark. He's uh said something about
someone he knew. He said, uh she wanted
a wedding, not a marriage,
>> which is like, oh, that hurt. Um but
yeah, so it's like this idea of like you
want the big glamour, you want the
event, you want like the outcome, but
you don't want the work that comes with
it. Like uh
>> the the process, the hassle, the haggle.
And like that's the thing, like they
want the passive income, the being the
boss, but maybe they don't want to build
a boring business.
>> I've got it. You know what? There's a
little headline here. If you look a
little down, it says boring businesses
are making millionaires.
>> I'd go to this article and I'd see if I
can get a number for these millionaires
or some sort of data point on those
those people that like
>> um you know, f Hey, first name. It's
kind of weird, but I recently checked
out these 20 new millionaires and
they're doing something completely
different to what everybody else is
talking about online right now. It's
actually kind of boring and it's kind of
silly how simple this is, but it
actually works. Or something like this.
You're kind of
>> This is your your opening lines.
>> Something like that.
>> Yeah, I like that. Um
there's like this weird sort of like
implicit narrative like I was just
checking this out and I saw this crazy
thing like and then you use something
that there's a something one of my
friends said too uh about like I have
all these cool references that people
give me and I try to remember them all.
It's like the idea of something's
un it's like ridiculously important, but
he says like it's
unusually or stupidly important. Like it
doesn't make sense,
>> right? And that thing you say like it's
kind of silly
>> that this would even work, right?
>> Yeah.
>> It's kind of like,
>> you know, you're sort of undercutting
>> weird, you know?
>> Yeah. You're undercutting the idea that
it's a lot of work. You're like, it's
it's really un it's unusually important.
That's I think what he said. He's like,
"It's unusually
simple that this is making money." But
yeah, that I I like that. I like all
that stuff that you just said. I like
that. And again, it has that weird sort
of surprising factoid sort of built into
it. You said, "I was just checking out
what is 20 new millionaires."
>> Oh, you know what? If you read down a
lot, there's this whole idea of like
renting out salon
salon suites to to beauty pros. It's
like I love this model because it's part
of a $300 billion industry. Now, I feel
like that's way more interesting to
bring up like a lot sooner, you know?
So, you could say something like maybe
um something along the lines of like,
"Hey, I was reading this article and I
got so like it was kind of weird and
interesting to me that there's all these
people making millions in this one niche
and the more I read, the more I realized
I know exactly what this business is.
It's what I've been doing for the last
10 years." It's like, you know, and it
kind of like then you pitch it, you
know, and you talk about something like
this. So yeah, I just think it like to
you know what we've been talking about
today is like you got to sit what I
would actually recommend that this
writer does in this case is uh sit and
write three to five different leads that
he kind of like just just riff it riff
some big ideas there but obviously like
go look at some proven formats go get
some inspiration from those formats and
then just riff a few leads and then
grade the lead about how you feel about
it like out of five or out of 10 like
how do I feel about this does this pull
me in? And then and then whichever one
you think is the strongest one and maybe
you lead off that idea.
>> One of the things that you might not
even notice because it's yourself like
you might have just overlooked it but
like a lot of times where you paused and
said we could bring this up earlier we
could bring this was like the points
where it was actually like hard data
>> like you paused on the numbers that were
interesting. You paused on the research.
>> Notice how you skipped over the generic
copy.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Mhm.
>> So, I mean, right there it sort of says
>> do more research.
>> Yeah.
>> Make it more fact, more concrete.
>> I think
>> it's boring, but it's but it but um it's
ow it's worth over $300 billion or
something. [laughter]
>> Yes.
>> $300 billion of boring businesses
secrets. Okay, let's have a look at this
last one and then uh let's let's wrap
up. I really appreciate it. It's been
really fun.
>> Yeah, man. This is basically what I do
every day. All right, so this last one,
this is for VS Shred. Can you guess
which of these everyday foods could help
your body burn fat faster? So, right
here, I'll just say thumbs up because
whenever I'm giving writers a choice of
pattern interrupt, they get three
choices. Take a look at this, which is
like a visual cue, or ask a question.
>> Those are like the two. The third one is
a breadcrumb, which is where you sort of
introduce a topic, but you don't give
enough. You give information like a
secret lead, if you could call it that
if you want,
>> maybe. So, but like uh I don't like to
let my newest guys use a breadcrumb
because they they they mess it up. They
don't know how to do it. So, anyway, can
you guess which of these could help your
body burn fat faster? Good question. Is
it cottage cheese, powdered protein
powder, eggs, bananas, chili peppers, or
avocado? I don't know. I'll reveal the
answer in just a second, and I guarantee
it'll shock you. So,
I'm not sold on that, but okay. What's
more, this one food item has been proven
in clinical studies by major Ivy League.
So, notice how that would have been a
trigger BS line. It'll shock you. So,
it's sort of following. So, notice here
he's got the two question pattern
interrupt. So, he's following the
formula pattern interrupt question, and
then he's got a trigger BS. But none of
them are especially strong.
>> Mhm. I think it's fine, but none of it's
like crazy. What's more, this one food
item has been proven in clinical
studies. Notice how he's automatically
leading into credibility.
>> You know, pattern interrupt, sugar
trigger, BS, credibility.
>> Um, Ivy League universities contain a
powerful fat burning ingredient that can
jumpst start even the slowest metabolism
and help melt away fat from all stubborn
areas of the body without restricting
calories. Cool. Better yet, you don't
need to do anything crazy. So, we still
he's like ramping up that skepticism. to
activate this fat burning ingredient
either. All you need to do is pair it
with a simple 30 second morning routine
that triggers a biological loophole.
>> Oh my god.
>> Discovered by Major Ivy League universe.
What do you what's got you chuckling?
>> That's just so It's just so funny, man.
Like copy 30 second morning routine that
triggers a biological loophole.
>> I think I feel like I've seen this
advertisement from Vshred. Like I feel
like they've run this. Um
>> everybody's always looking for a
biological loophole. With the fitness
industry, it's always like, how do I do
the least work? Like, like work out the
least and eat whatever the hell I want
and still get in shape. That's like
literally all you're selling and in
different ways.
>> Well, they figure it out now. It was
Empic, right? Ain't that what it does?
That's the whole point.
>> Uh, so you can start releasing stubborn
fat automatically. So, there it is.
Automatically from your belly. I mean,
this is pretty sophisticated. It's got
it's ramping up the skepticism. It's
ramping up the promise. It has a pattern
error up. It's dropping credibility
though. It does say major Ivy League
twice. I don't think that's a I think
it's fine. What I'm saying by that is is
two times he kind of just says major Ivy
League. You could have done more. You
could have been more specific. You could
have again added the texture. We've
talked about texture a lot today, like
dimensionalize it. When you create that
space, I call that letting it breathe.
You you not only like enhance that one
piece of proof, but you add narrative.
you add and you can beef up the copy
without the reader experiencing any sort
of like dullness like it doesn't get old
because you added texture. As a matter
of fact, it gets more interesting.
>> Yeah.
>> And again, this is something like
copywriters, they especially insecure
copywriting, they feel like they need to
be sufficiently vague. And it's like,
no, no, no. The more specific you are
without naming it, the real intrigue is
in that. the more specific you can be
without actually dropping the name of
what it is, the more concrete detail you
can provide, the more you'll have me
hooked. And then you drop a and it's not
whatever is the most obvious thing and
it's not avocados. Oh [__] what is it?
All right, so better yet, you don't need
to do anything crazy to activate it.
Pair it with the routine kickstarts
metabolism. You can release belly fat.
Even I was surprised. So, this is
addressing that skepticism
because although I've helped 5.1 million
people credibility, he's got three
pieces of cred. 5 million A-list
celebrities. No, he don't. Has two
pieces. Transform their bodies. I'd
never heard of this quick fat burning
loophole. Honestly, makes fat diets like
keto look like a complete
>> There's the it's what it's not. There's
this it's not this and it's not that
section. It makes fat diets like keto or
crazy workouts look like a complete
joke.
Yeah.
You see, most people think they eat
pounds of bland chicken and broccoli,
but what they don't know is they can
easily start releasing stubborn belly
fat if they only fix this one thing, the
broken metab. See, identifies it right
there. It's about metabolism.
>> Um,
>> can I jump in here real quick?
>> Yeah, go for it.
>> So, when I read this section, I feel
like we we had a really good buildup.
>> Mhm.
And then we're kind of like this one
thing they don't know is that they can
easily start releasing stubborn belly
fat if they only fix this one thing is
almost a repeat of the sentence earlier
like so you can start releasing stubborn
belly fat automatically from your belly,
arms, hips, thighs. So there's no new
stuff there. There's nothing that feels
um yeah like it doesn't continue the
idea in my mind and then it's like fix
this one thing and then it just kind of
like falls flat their broken metabolism.
>> I feel like there's there's an
opportunity here in that little section
to really build up better.
>> Um
>> so what's funny about this is when I see
him say but what they don't know that
line
>> where he goes into their broken
metabolism that's the end of the lead
for me. We're now in the problem section
and the rules change.
>> There's rules for the lead and then
there's rules for the body copy. And the
problem in my world view is the problem
is a body copy section. And now yes, I
do think that there's some things we
could address with the problem section.
The problem section apart from the lead
here, I think is could use some help.
It says in fact metabolism is broken
metabolism is so common
University of North Carolina confirmed
12% of Americans are metabolically
healthy. So you've ever started a new
diet and maybe lost a few pounds your
metabolism is broken too and soon found
the pounds came back with a vengeance.
Yeah. So
yeah, what they're doing here is they're
trying to set you up for it's not your
fault.
Um, I do feel like get to the it's not
your fault thing a little bit faster.
Uh, there's there's two things that we
could address. I think we can go back to
something that you said about the lead.
So, I mentioned they said major Ivy
League universities twice and you said
you keep saying stubborn belly fat
texture. Add add concrete detail like
get a little bit. I would say like I
want to salute that the structure here
is pretty fair. Like he's ramping up
that skepticism.
He's got a mechanism. He's got some
cred. I helped 5.1 million people and
A-list celebrities.
I'd never heard of this.
So again, same thing here. I've helped
A-list celebrities like
Jessica Alba, Mike Tyson, Bradley
Cooper. You know, you could do
There's a bunch of stuff you could do
here. You could add a little bit more.
Again, I I would call it like letting it
breathe. Like, pause for a minute. Don't
just rush to the next section. Like,
give me some texture for each of these.
>> I actually think a really good way to to
do that here would be like I'd never
heard of this quick daily fat burning
loophole. If that's the idea that it's
this quick little routine in the morning
and then we switch to saying like you
need to fix this one thing.
>> To me, it feels like a little bit of a
disconnect. What I would say is like,
you know, um most people think they need
to eat pound. Um and honestly, it makes
fat diets like keto, crazy workouts like
CrossFit look like a complete joke. I
might even say he has some like drop a
couple of testimonials like like John
John recently added this simple routine
to his morning and like he went from
struggling like training six days a week
at the gym to now only working out at
the gym like one or two times a week,
eating what he wants or something. And
like two or three of those, it's like
these are just regular people. And the
thing is, and then you go into like it's
not your fault stuff and then maybe you
go into the mechanism.
>> The other thing on that note, there's,
you know, I talked about double mumbo
jumbo earlier. We've got the food,
right? We've got the food and then you
got to pair it with a 30 secondond
morning routine and then we have a
biological loophole.
>> Mhm.
>> So, we've got like triple mumbo jumbo.
We've got three things that are
undefined and vague. We don't know.
>> Triple mumbo jumbo.
>> Yeah. I'm not sure exactly
what our mechanism is.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and then like what you say the way
that sort of manifested in your
experience is like what is is it a
loophole or is it like a diet or is it
like a routine? Like what is it?
>> And so I think again like all that stuff
goes back to the idea about the pin
thing that I talked about a thumbtack.
>> Yeah.
>> Um he does keep it going. This food item
has been proven in clinical studies by
major to blah blah blah to jump start
slowest metabolism. Then metabolism is a
thing too. The broken metabolism. So
again like I feel like the structure is
pretty good. I feel like the copy is
pretty good. Um this I've seen worse. Uh
there's little things that you could do
like you could get a lot more concrete
with the detail. You could mix it up
where you're not repeating the same like
cred like Ivy League universities and
belly fat or whatever. I think it's okay
to point out multiple times to stubborn
belly fat. That's what they they
probably are focused on anyway. They
want they want to hear they're going to
>> lay around it though. Maybe something
different, right?
>> Yeah. So, you could you could Okay, you
could add texture. start releasing
stubborn belly fat and
cankles, thighs, whatever other weird
like insecure place that people hold
weight where they're like not good, not
happy about it.
>> Um,
you know what? Actually, from what you
just said there as well, it's like he's
adding texture, but he's adding it where
the mechanism is instead of keeping that
kind of clean line all the way down. I
think that it's like some of the lines
where you would want to have different
wording, you'd want to say it in
slightly different ways that to keep it
more interesting. That's where he's made
it the same. And in the mechanism where
you're supposed to make it more curious
and you're supposed to build up the one
idea, you build bigger and bigger.
That's where he kind of introduces the
mechanism from like it doesn't feel like
the same mechanism. Like at one moment
here I'm thinking, oh, it's one secret
one. Oh, it's a loophole. Oh, so you
know, like we're talking about, right?
So
>> yeah. So here's what I'll say. You said
testimonials. So, I mean, you and I are
kind of bouncing off some of the same
frequencies here. He's got the idea of a
daily fat that I've never heard of this
quick daily fat burning loophole. And
honestly, it makes fad diets like keto
and crossfit look like a joke. Um, and
right there he says, you see, most
people think that's where he moves into
a transition to a problem section,
right? What's missing from uh pattern
interrupt, trigger BS, credibility, demo
results,
>> demo results,
>> right? So right here, he could have gone
into demo results. And with a demo of
results, you can do a lot of this stuff
that you're describing, you can
basically state a claim. So
if his his claim would be it makes
CrossFit look like a joke, his next demo
result would be look at Trisha. She did
CrossFit for three years and only ended
up bulky and
heavy and unhappy.
>> And after four weeks of doing this, But
the thing is that's the whole thing.
Like if you're going to mention CrossFit
and a claim and then you're going to go
into a demo of results, then it has to
be
>> has to be tied together.
>> But that would also do a lot of the
stuff that we're talking about. Like
this is probably the hardest part of
copy chiefing is you have to see what
isn't there.
>> Cuz like when we're sitting here trying
to say this word or that word, we might
be like fixing a problem like well the
problem is actually the absence of
something. The problem is the negative
space or the like it's not the things
that's on the page again like the
structure pretty okay. I've seen worse
like he seems to be following actually
and this is something else like I didn't
I always have to make like this sort of
disclaimer the structure my structure is
not something I invented. It's an
amalgamation of all the promos I've read
that made a million dollars. I took the
average. This is why I say we're kind of
like a AI or the way I approach this is
sort of like AI. I took the average of
all the million-dollar promos over 10
years that I've studied approximately 10
is eight. And this is the structure that
is the most average of that group.
>> And so when I'm looking at this, I'm
saying this follows the structure. It's
following the average of million dollar
promotional copy except where the [__]
are the results, you know? So with that
he can do make the claim start the demo
results. One of the things you have to
do in your early well you don't have to
you could just say they they lost 20
pounds they lost 20 pounds they lost 50
pounds you could do that it's like level
one stuff to add texture you'll do a
technique that I call drama
which is just conflict and the [snorts]
conflict is always us versus them. So
who would be the them in that example
that I gave?
>> Which one? The crossbow one.
>> Crossfit. Crossfit's them. Us. She did
this. She went running every day with
her CrossFit community. She paid for
that's things we can talk about. [music]
>> She paid hundreds of dollars to join an
exclusive gym, sweat to death in a air
conditionless garage, lifting heavy
weights and carrying sacks of sand on
her back, only to end up looking like
She-Hulk. [laughter]
Four weeks later on the special
metabolism loophole.
>> Yeah.
>> She's over here [music] skinny enough to
impress Tyra Banks. Like she's she's
runway ready and can barely stand up on
her own two feet. She lost so much
weight. So um yeah, you can you can make
all those little again there's little uh
that's what I'm talking about. Every one
of these lines is an opportunity to add
what you call texture or technique.
>> There's an opportunity to slide a
technique in there. How would I know
what technique? read the [__] copy,
read copy, read, copy, read, copy, and
start making notes of all the individual
techniques that you notice inside of a
demo results section. What I do is I
equip people with the tools to recognize
the sections. Now, people who watch this
can sit down and recopy and they'll be
like, "Huh, pattern interrupt.
>> Yeah.
>> Trigger BS demo results credibility."
[music] And they'll start to block it
themselves. And they're like, "How did
they do their credibility?" They did it
one, two, three different ways. Now they
have three new arrows in their quiver
for credibility forever. And you get
that from reading copy, reading copy,
reading copy.
>> I love it, man. [music] So, where can
people find you? Where can people learn
this stuff from you?
>> Uh, so my website would be copyp
squad.net.
>> Okay.
>> Went for the comm, couldn't get it.
So,net it is.
>> Love [music] it, man. If you want to
learn more, go to copysquad.net.
Leave comments, leave questions. If you
have any, I can ask him. And yeah, Kyle,
thanks so much for joining me, man. It's
been fun.
>> Thanks for having me.
>> Yeah.